Guide to the Book-of-the-Month Club Records
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Book-of-the-Month Club records
1946-1979
YCAL MSS 278
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
39.94
(70 boxes)
The collection consists of proofs and "first reader reports" that document a component of the selection process for titles that became Book-of-the-Month Club selections. The proofs are pre-publication copies of manuscripts, used by Book-of-the-Month Club judges to select titles. The reports comprise reviews by in-house editors and outside readers of manuscripts under consideration for publication. They were written by a wide variety of individuals including Rosemary Benet, Basil Davenport, Elizabeth Wynne Easton, Roger Pippett, John Sherry, Russell Thacher, Ralph Thompson, and Leon Wilson.
Book-of-the-Month Club
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Book-of-the-Month Club, circa 1978 and 2000.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
History
The Book-of-the-Month Club (BOMC) was founded in 1926 by Harry Scherman (1887-1969) in partnership with Maxwell Sackheim (1890-1982) and Robert K. Haas (1890-1964). Created to satisfy a perceived demand for quality literature that could not be met outside of urban centers, it was one of a number of direct-mail clubs developed in the 1920s, including the Literary Guild and Dollar Book Club. The BOMC went public in 1947, though the Scherman family maintained a controlling interest until sale of their shares in 1977 to Time Inc.
The BOMC sold new releases to its membership through recommendations published in a monthly catalog. Pre-publication manuscripts were submitted to the BOMC for review and were considered through a tiered system of in-house and outside editors culminating in an editorial board, referred to as judges in BOMC literature, that met monthly to consider vetted submissions.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of proofs and "first reader reports" that document a component of the selection process for titles that became Book-of-the-Month Club recommendations. The proofs are pre-publication copies of manuscripts, used by Book-of-the-Month Club judges to select titles. They can be located in Series I and Series III.
The reports comprise reviews by in-house editors and outside readers of manuscripts under consideration for publication. They were written by a wide variety of individuals including Rosemary Benet, Basil Davenport, Elizabeth Wynne Easton, Roger Pippett, John Sherry, Russell Thacher, Ralph Thompson, and Leon Wilson.
Arrangement
Organized into three series: I. Manuscripts, circa 1959-1978. II. First-reader Reports, circa 1946-1962. III. Additional Manuscripts (July 2000 Acquisition), circa 1951-1979.
American literature -- 20th Century; Book clubs (Bookselling) -- United States; Books -- United States -- Reviews; Benét, Rosemary, 1900-1962; Davenport, Basil, 1905-1966; Easton, Elizabeth Wynne; Pippett, Roger; Sherry, John, 1923-1999; Thacher, Russell, 1919-1990; Thompson, Ralph, 1904-1979; Wilson, Leon; Book-of-the-Month Club
- Manuscripts, circa 1959-1978; Series I; (36 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  The series consists of pre-publication copies, mostly galley proofs, of manuscripts submitted to the Book-of-the-Month Club to be considered for selection as a featured title. The manuscripts were most likely prepared and distributed for judges and many have stickers affixed, designating the copy as an "A" book. Although these galleys often contain editorial notes in the reproduction, they are generally unmarked by the readers at the Book-of-the-Month Club.
  Related Archival Materials note
  Additional titles are listed in Series III, which consists of the July 2000 acquisition of this collection.
  Arrangement
  The series is arranged alphabetically by author.
  - Agee, James. The letters of James Agee to Father Flye, circa 1962 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - Auchincloss, Louis. Edith Wharton: a woman in her time, circa 1971 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Baldwin, James. If Beale Street could talk, circa 1974 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Bowles, Paul. Without stopping, circa 1971 (Box 1, Folder 5-9)
  - Buck, Pearl S. (Pearl Sydenstricker). The three daughters of Madame Liang, circa 1969 (Box 2, Folder 10-15)
  - Burroughs, William S. Kentucky ham, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 16-18)
  - Caldwell, Erskine. Summertime island, circa 1969 (Box 2, Folder 19-21)
  - Callaghan, Morley. That summer in Paris: memories of tangled friendships with Hemingway, Fitzgerald, and some others, circa 1963 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Chase, Ilka. The sounds of home, circa 1971 (Box 3, Folder 23-26)
  - Childs, Marquis W. (Marquis William). Taint of innocence, circa 1967 (Box 3, Folder 27-31)
  - Connelly, Marc. "In order of appearance", circa 1968 (Box 4, Folder 32-35)
    General note
    Published under title Voices offstage; a book of memoirs
  - Cozzens, James Gould. Children and others, circa 1964 (Box 4, Folder 36-41)
  - Davenport, Marcia. Too strong for fantasy, circa 1967 (Box 5, Folder 42-48)
  - Deutsch, Babette. The collected poems of Babette Deutsch, circa 1969 (Box 6, Folder 49-52)
  - Dickey, James
    - Deliverance, circa 1970 (Box 6, Folder 53-56)
    - Sorties, circa 1971 (Box 6, Folder 57-59)
  - Dillard, Annie. Pilgrim at Tinker Creek, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 60-65)
  - Donleavy, J. P. (James Patrick). A fairy tale of New York, circa 1973 (Box 8, Folder 66-72)
  - Drury, Allen. Preserve and protect: a novel, circa 1968 (Box 9, Folder 73-80)
  - Farrell, James T. (James Thomas)
    - The invisible swords, circa 1971 (Box 9, Folder 81-83)
    - The invisible swords, circa 1971 (Box 10, Folder 84-89)
    - Olive and Mary Anne, circa 1977 (Box 10, Folder 90-92)
  - Faulkner, William. The mansion, 1959 (Box 11, Folder 93)
  - Gibson, William
    - A mass for the dead, circa 1968 (Box 11, Folder 94-95)
    - A mass for the dead, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 96-100)
  - Gill, Brendan. "Naturally, one wants to be a star", Undated (Box 13, Folder 101-102)
    Unpublished manuscript, later published, in part, as Tallulah (1972)
  - Gordimer, Nadine. A guest of honour, circa 1970 (Box 13, Folder 103-110)
  - Grau, Shirley Ann
    - The condor passes, circa 1971 (Box 13, Folder 111-112)
    - The condor passes, circa 1971 (Box 14, Folder 113-118)
  - Gunther, John
    - John Gunther's inside Australia, circa 1972 (Box 15, Folder 119-124)
    - John Gunther's inside Australia, circa 1972 (Box 16, Folder 125-128)
  - Hahn, Emily
    - Fractured emerald: Ireland, circa 1971 (Box 16, Folder 129-130)
    - Fractured emerald: Ireland, circa 1971 (Box 17, Folder 131-134)
  - Hellman, Lillian
    - Scoundrel time (copy 1), circa 1972 (Box 17, Folder 135-136)
    - Scoundrel time (copy 1), circa 1972 (Box 18, Folder 137)
      Includes black and white photograhs (5)
    - Scoundrel time (copy 2), circa 1972 (Box 18, Folder 138-140)
      Includes black and white photographs (5)
  - Hemingway, Ernest. By-line Ernest Hemingway, 1966 (Box 19, Folder 141-142)
  - Herlihy, James Leo
    - The season of the witch, circa 1971 (Box 20, Folder 143-148)
    - The season of the witch, circa 1971 (Box 21, Folder 149)
  - Hersey, John
    - Under the eye of the storm, circa 1967 (Box 21, Folder 150-153)
    - The walnut door, circa 1977 (Box 21, Folder 154)
    - The walnut door, circa 1977 (Box 22, Folder 155-157)
  - Horgan, Paul
    - Everything to live for (copy 1), circa 1968 (Box 22, Folder 158-161)
    - Everything to live for (copy 2), circa 1968 (Box 22, Folder 162-165)
  - Howar, Barbara. Laughing all the way, circa 1973 (Box 23, Folder 166-173)
  - Johnston, Johanna. The heart that would not hold: a biography of Washington Irving, circa 1971 (Box 24, Folder 174-179)
  - Jones, James. A touch of danger, circa 1973 (Box 25, Folder 180-187)
  - Jones, Wally. Black champions challenge American sports, circa 1972 (Box 25, Folder 188-190)
  - Knowles, John
    - Indian Summer, circa 1966 (Box 25, Folder 191-192)
    - Indian Summer, circa 1966 (Box 26, Folder 193-194)
  - Longstreet, Stephen. The Pedlock inheritance, circa 1972 (Box 26, Folder 195-200)
  - Lord, Walter. A time to stand, circa 1961 (Box 26, Folder 201-203)
  - Macdonald, Ross. Sleeping beauty, circa 1973 (Box 27, Folder 204-208)
  - Malamud, Bernard
    - "Two writers", circa 1971 (Box 27, Folder 209)
      Unpublished under given title
    - "Two writers", circa 1971 (Box 28, Folder 210-211)
  - McCarthy, Mary. The mask of state: Watergate portraits, circa 1974 (Box 28, Folder 212)
  - McGinley, Phyllis
    - "The hearth has its reasons", circa 1964 (Box 28, Folder 213-215)
    - "The hearth has its reasons", circa 1964 (Box 29, Folder 216)
  - Moore, Marianne. O to be a dragon, circa 1959 (Box 29, Folder 217)
  - Morris, Willie
    - The last of the southern girls, 1972 (Box 29, Folder 218-223)
    - North toward home, circa 1967 (Box 30, Folder 224-230)
  - Nabokov, Vladimir Vladimirovich. Transparent things: a novel, circa 1972 (Box 30, Folder 231-232)
  - Shapiro, Karl. Edsel, circa 1971 (Box 30, Folder 233-238)
  - Slavitt, David R.
    - Eclogues of Virgil, circa 1971 (Box 31, Folder 239)
    - The Outer Mongolian, circa 1973 (Box 31, Folder 240-242)
  - Stegner, Wallace Earle
    - Angle of repose, circa 1971 (Box 31, Folder 243-245)
    - Angle of repose, circa 1971 (Box 32, Folder 246-251)
    - The uneasy chair: a biography of Bernard DeVoto, 1973 (Box 33, Folder 252-262)
  - Updike, John
    - Marry me: a romance, circa 1976 (Box 33, Folder 263-266)
    - Marry me: a romance, circa 1976 (Box 34, Folder 267)
  - Vidal, Gore. Kalki: a novel, 1977 (Box 34, Folder 268-273)
  - Welty, Eudora. The optimist's daughter, circa 1972 (Box 35, Folder 274-276)
  - Wilder, Thornton
    - Theophilus North (copy 1), circa 1973 (Box 35, Folder 277-284)
    - Theophilus North (copy 2), circa 1973 (Box 35, Folder 285-286)
    - Theophilus North (copy 2), circa 1973 (Box 36, Folder 287-292)
  - Wilk, Max. The moving picture boys, circa 1978 (Box 36, Folder 293-294)
  - Wilson, Edmund. "A window in Russia", 1971 (Box 36, Folder 295-299)
    Published under title A window on Russia, for the use of foreign readers (1972)
- First-Reader Reports, circa 1946-1962; Series II; (14 boxes)
  The First Reader Reports consist of typescript reviews of manuscripts, written by a combination of in-house editors and outside readers. The reports helped the Book-of-the-Month Club select titles from among manuscripts submitted by publishers and individuals. The reports are typed on a given form stipulating the institutional expectations for the reports, with specific questions guiding the reader to determine whether or not the given manuscript should be considered by the judges at the monthly meetings.
  The reports were written by a wide variety of reviewers, including Rosemary Benet, Basil Davenport, Elizabeth Wynne Easton, Roger Pippett, John Sherry, Russell Thacher, Ralph Thompson, and Leon Wilson.
  The series is arranged loosely chronologically, with two pre-designated categories, "African diaspora history and literature" and "American literature" filed at the beginning. Reviews of books in these topics are also included among the chronologically arranged materials.
  - African diaspora history and literature, circa 1946-1960 (Box 37, Folder 300-303)
  - American literature, circa 1946-1960 (Box 37, Folder 304-322)
  - General
    - circa 1946 (Box 37, Folder 323-332)
    - circa 1946 (Box 38, Folder 333-336)
    - circa 1948 (Box 38, Folder 337-355)
    - circa 1949 (Box 38, Folder 356-365)
    - circa 1951 (Box 39, Folder 366-367)
    - circa 1952 (Box 39, Folder 368-398)
    - circa 1953 (Box 39, Folder 399-403)
    - circa 1953 (Box 40, Folder 404-433)
    - circa 1954 (Box 40, Folder 434-439)
    - circa 1954 (Box 41, Folder 440-449)
    - circa 1955 (Box 41, Folder 450-472)
    - circa 1955 (Box 42, Folder 473-474)
    - circa 1956 (Box 42, Folder 475-504)
    - circa 1957 (Box 42, Folder 505-507)
    - circa 1957 (Box 43, Folder 508-523)
    - circa 1958 (Box 43, Folder 524-543)
    - circa 1958 (Box 44, Folder 544-558)
    - circa 1959 (Box 44, Folder 559-578)
    - circa 1959 (Box 45, Folder 579)
    - 1960 (Box 45, Folder 580-595)
    - circa 1960 (Box 45, Folder 596-610)
    - 1961 (Box 45, Folder 611-612)
    - 1961 (Box 46, Folder 613-644)
    - 1962 (Box 46, Folder 645-648)
    - 1962 (Box 47, Folder 649-654)
    - 1960 (Box 68, Folder 956-958)
    - Undated (Box 68, Folder 959-963)
    - Undated (Box 69, Folder 964-970)
    - Undated (Box 70, Folder 971)
- Additional Manuscripts (July 2000 Acquisition), circa 1951-1979; Series III; (20 boxes)
  The series consists of bound and galley proofs of works published by the club.
  Additional manuscripts can be found in Series I.
  - Ai. Cruelty, 1973 May 11 (Box 48, Folder 655)
  - Alfred, William. Hogan's goat, circa 1966 (Box 48, Folder 656)
  - Amis, Kingsley
    - The Anti-Death League, circa 1966 (Box 48, Folder 657)
    - One fat Englishman, circa 1964 (Box 48, Folder 658)
  - Ammons, A. R. Sphere: the form of a motion, 1974 Apr 17 (Box 48, Folder 659)
  - Appleman, Philip. Open doorways, 1976 Jun 29 (Box 48, Folder 660)
  - Auden, W. H. (Wystan Hugh)
    - Collected poems, circa 1976 (Box 48, Folder 661-662)
    - The dyer's hand, circa 1962 (Box 48, Folder 663)
    - Forewords and Afterwords, 1973 March (Box 67, Folder 954)
    - Homage to Clio, 1960 Apr 29 (Box 48, Folder 664)
    - The orators, circa 1967 (Box 48, Folder 665)
    - The Protestant mystics, 1964 May 5 (Box 48, Folder 666)
  - Baldwin, James
    - The amen corner, circa 1967 (Box 48, Folder 667)
    - Another country, circa 1962 (Box 48, Folder 668)
    - Blues for Mister Charlie, circa 1964 (Box 48, Folder 669)
    - Go tell it on the mountain, circa 1963 (Box 48, Folder 670)
    - Notes of a native son, circa 1963 (Box 48, Folder 671)
  - Basso, Hamilton. A touch of the dragon, circa 1964 (Box 49, Folder 672)
  - Bellow, Saul. The last analysis, circa 1965 (Box 49, Folder 673)
  - Berry, Wendell
    - The broken ground, circa 1964 (Box 49, Folder 674)
    - Openings, circa 1968 (Box 49, Folder 675)
  - Berryman, John. Love & Fame, circa 1970 (Box 49, Folder 676)
  - Bishop, Elizabeth
    - The complete poems, circa 1969 (Box 49, Folder 677)
    - Questions of travel, circa 1951 (Box 49, Folder 678)
  - Bly, Robert. Sleepers joining hands, circa 1972 (Box 49, Folder 679)
  - Booth, Philip E. "Weathers and edges", circa 1966 (Box 49, Folder 680)
    Published under title Weather and edges
  - Borges, Jorge Luis. The book of sand (2 copies), circa 1978 (Box 49, Folder 681-682)
  - Borland, Hal. Hill country harvest, circa 1967 (Box 49, Folder 683)
  - Botsford, Keith. The march-man, circa 1964 (Box 49, Folder 684)
  - Bowen, Catherine Drinker. Family portrait, 1970 Jun 25 (Box 49, Folder 685)
  - Bowen, Elizabeth. Pictures and conversations (2 copies), 1974 Sep 30 (Box 49, Folder 686-687)
  - Boyle, Kay. Nothing ever breaks except the heart, circa 1966 (Box 49, Folder 688)
  - Bradbury, Ray
    - I Sing the Body Electric, circa 1969 (Box 49, Folder 689)
    - The machineries of joy, circa 1964 (Box 49, Folder 690)
  - Brautigan, Richard. Loading mercury with a pitchfork, 1976 Mar 25 (Box 50, Folder 691)
  - Brooks, Gwendolyn. In the Mecca, circa 1968 (Box 50, Folder 692)
  - Buchanan, David. The treasure of Auchinleck: the story of the Boswell papers, circa 1974 (Box 50, Folder 693)
  - Burgess, Anthony
    - Beard's Roman women, 1976 Jun 7 (Box 50, Folder 694)
    - The clockwork testament; or, Enderby's end, 1974 Oct 24 (Box 50, Folder 695)
    - 1985, circa 1978 (Box 50, Folder 696)
    - The wanting seed, circa 1963 (Box 50, Folder 697)
  - Burgin, Richard. Conversations with Jorge Luis Borges, circa 1969 (Box 50, Folder 698)
  - Burroughs, William S. Kentucky ham, 1973 Feb 28 (Box 50, Folder 699)
  - Bynner, Witter
    - The Chinese translations, 1978 May 29 (Box 50, Folder 700)
    - Light verse and satires, 1978 May 29 (Box 50, Folder 701)
    - Selected poems, 1978 May 29 (Box 50, Folder 702)
  - Cabell, James Branch. As I remember it, circa 1955 (Box 50, Folder 703)
  - Cane, Melville
    - All and sundry, circa 1968 (Box 50, Folder 704)
    - Bullet-hunting and other new poems, circa 1960 (Box 50, Folder 705)
    - Eloquent April, circa 1971 (Box 50, Folder 706)
    - The first firefly, circa 1974 (Box 50, Folder 707)
    - So that it flower, circa 1966 (Box 50, Folder 708)
  - Capote, Truman
    - The Thanksgiving visitor, circa 1968 (Box 51, Folder 709)
    - Selected writings, 1963 Feb (Box 51, Folder 710)
  - Carroll, Paul. Odes, circa 1969 (Box 51, Folder 711)
  - Cary, Joyce. Selected essays, circa 1976 (Box 51, Folder 712)
  - Chandler, Raymond. Killer in the rain, 1964 (Box 51, Folder 713)
  - Chase, Mary Ellen. A Journey to Boston, circa 1965 (Box 51, Folder 714)
  - Cheever, John. The Brigadier and the golf widow, circa 1964 (Box 51, Folder 715)
  - Christie, Agatha
    - Akhnaton: a play in three acts, 1973 Mar 1 (Box 51, Folder 716)
    - Postern of fate, 1973 Aug 16 (Box 51, Folder 717)
  - Clark, Eleanor. The oysters of Locmariaquer, circa 1964 (Box 51, Folder 718)
  - Coffin, Tristram. Not to the swift, circa 1961 (Box 51, Folder 719)
  - Cole, William. Poems, one line and longer, 1973 Jun 28 (Box 51, Folder 720)
  - Compton-Burnett, I. ( Ivy). The last and the first, 1971 Sep (Box 51, Folder 721)
  - Conrad, Joseph. Congo diary and other uncollected pieces, circa 1978 (Box 51, Folder 722)
  - Corn, Alfred. A call in the midst of the crowd, 1978 Apr (Box 51, Folder 723)
  - Cowley, Malcolm. Blue Juniata: collected poems, circa 1968 (Box 51, Folder 724)
  - Creeley, Robert. The gold diggers, circa 1965 (Box 51, Folder 725)
  - Cummings, E. E. (Edward Estlin). 73 poems, circa 1963 (Box 51, Folder 726)
  - Dahlberg, Edward
    - The Confessions of Edward Dahlberg, 1971 Feb (Box 52, Folder 727)
    - Epitaphs of Our Times, 1966 (Box 52, Folder 728)
  - Damon, S. Foster (Samuel Foster). The Moulton tragedy, circa 1970 (Box 52, Folder 729)
  - Day Lewis, C. (Cecil). Requiem For the Living, 1964 Jan 29 (Box 52, Folder 730)
  - Dennis, Patrick. The joyous season, circa 1964 (Box 52, Folder 731)
  - Devlin, Denis. Selected poems, circa 1963 (Box 52, Folder 732)
  - Dinesen, Isak. "Entertainments and posthumous tales", circa 1977 (Box 52, Folder 733)
    Published under title Carnival: entertainments and posthumous tales
  - Donleavy, J. P. (James Patrick)
    - Meet my maker, the mad molecule, circa 1964 (Box 52, Folder 734)
    - The saddest summer of Samuel S, circa 1966 (Box 52, Folder 735)
    - A singular man, circa 1963 (Box 52, Folder 736)
  - Doyle, Arthur Conan, Sir. The demon device, 1978 Jul (Box 52, Folder 737)
  - Drabble, Margaret. The millstone, circa 1966 (Box 52, Folder 738)
  - Dubie, Norman. The city of the Olesha fruit, circa 1979 (Box 52, Folder 739)
  - Durrell, Gerald
    - Birds, beasts, and relatives, circa 1969 (Box 52, Folder 740)
    - The stationary ark, circa 1976 (Box 52, Folder 741)
  - Eiseley, Loren C. The star thrower, 1978 Jun (Box 52, Folder 742)
  - Engle, Paul. A woman unashamed and other poems, circa 1965 (Box 52, Folder 743)
  - Farrell, James T.
    - The collected poems of James T. Farrell, circa 1965 (Box 52, Folder 744)
    - Lonely for the Future, circa 1966 (Box 52, Folder 745)
    - Reflections at fifty, circa 1954 (Box 53, Folder 746)
    - The silence of history, circa 1963 (Box 53, Folder 747)
    - What time collects, circa 1964 (Box 53, Folder 748)
  - Faulkner, William
    - Essays, speeches & public letters, circa 1966 (Box 53, Folder 749)
    - A fable, circa 1954 (Box 53, Folder 750)
    - Requiem for a nun, circa 1951 (Box 53, Folder 751)
  - Feldman, Irving. Lost originals, circa 1972 (Box 53, Folder 752)
  - Ferril, Thomas Hornsby. Words for Denver and other poems, circa 1966 (Box 53, Folder 753)
  - Field, Andrew. Nabokov: his life in art, circa 1967 (Box 53, Folder 754)
  - Fitts, Dudley, trans. Sixty poems of Martial in translation, circa 1967 (Box 53, Folder 755)
  - Forster, E. M. (Edward Morgan). Maurice, circa 1971 (Box 53, Folder 756)
  - Freeman, Arthur. Estrangements, circa 1966 (Box 53, Folder 757)
  - Galbraith, Georgie Starbuck. Have one on me, circa 1963 (Box 53, Folder 758)
  - Gallico, Paul. Further confessions of a story writer, circa 1961 (Box 53, Folder 759)
  - Garrett, George P. Do, Lord, remember me, circa 1965 (Box 53, Folder 760)
  - Garrigue, Jean. A water walk by Villa d'Este, circa 1959 (Box 53, Folder 761)
  - Goedicke, Patricia. Between oceans, circa 1968 (Box 54, Folder 762)
  - Golding, William
    - The pyramid, circa 1967 (Box 54, Folder 763-764)
    - The spire, circa 1964 (Box 54, Folder 765)
  - Goldman, William
    - Father's day, circa 1970 (Box 54, Folder 766)
    - The season, circa 1969 (Box 54, Folder 767)
  - Gordimer, Nadine
    - The late bourgeois world, circa 1966 (Box 54, Folder 768)
    - Occasion for loving, undated (Box 54, Folder 769)
    - Six feet of the country: fifteen short stories, circa 1956 (Box 54, Folder 770)
  - Gordon, Caroline. Old Red and other stories, circa 1963 (Box 54, Folder 771)
  - Graves, Robert
    - Collected short stories, circa 1964 (Box 54, Folder 772)
    - New collected poems, circa 1977 (Box 54, Folder 773)
    - Poems about love, circa 1968 (Box 54, Folder 774)
    - The reader over your shoulder, circa 1971 (Box 54, Folder 775)
  - Grumbach, Doris. The company she kept, circa 1967 (Box 54, Folder 776)
  - Halévy, Daniel. My friend Degas, circa 1964 (Box 54, Folder 777)
  - Halpern, Daniel. Life among others, circa 1978 (Box 54, Folder 778)
  - Harris, Richard. I, in the membership of my days, 1973 Jun 28 (Box 54, Folder 779)
  - Harrison, Jim
    - Farmer, 1976 Apr 20 (Box 55, Folder 780)
    - A Good Day to Die, 1973 Apr 19 (Box 55, Folder 781)
    - Plain Song, circa 1965 (Box 55, Folder 782)
    - Locations, circa 1968 (Box 55, Folder 783)
  - Heller, Joseph. Catch-22, circa 1973 (Box 55, Folder 784)
  - Hellman, Lillian
    - Pentimento, 1973 Jun 29 (Box 55, Folder 785)
    - An unfinished woman: a memoir, circa 1969 (Box 55, Folder 786)
  - Hersey, John
    - Here to stay, circa 1963 (Box 55, Folder 787)
    - White lotus, circa 1965 (Box 55, Folder 788)
  - Hillyer, Robert. Collected poems, circa 1961 (Box 55, Folder 789)
  - Himes, Chester. The heat's on, circa 1966 (Box 55, Folder 790)
  - Hoffman, Daniel. The center of attention, circa 1974 (Box 55, Folder 791)
  - Hoffman, Jill. Mink coat, 1973 Aug 16 (Box 55, Folder 792)
  - Hope, A.D. (Alec Derwent). New poems, 1965-1969, circa 1970 (Box 55, Folder 793)
  - Horgan, Paul
    - Citizen of New Salem, circa 1961 (Box 55, Folder 794)
    - The heroic triad, circa 1970 (Box 55, Folder 795)
    - The peach stone: stories from four decades, circa 1967 (Box 55, Folder 796)
    - Things as they are, circa 1964 (Box 55, Folder 797)
  - Hughes, Ted. Selected poems, circa 1974 (Box 55, Folder 798)
  - Huxley, Aldous. Collected poems of Aldous Huxley, circa 1971 (Box 56, Folder 799)
    Published under title Collected poetry of Aldous Huxley
  - Huxley, Laura Archera. This timeless moment, circa 1968 (Box 56, Folder 800-802)
  - Isherwood, Christopher
    - Christopher and his kind, circa 1975 (Box 56, Folder 803)
    - Ramakrishna and his disciples, circa 1965 (Box 56, Folder 804)
    - A single man, circa 1964 (Box 56, Folder 805)
  - Jackson, Shirley. Special delivery, circa 1960 (Box 56, Folder 806)
  - Jarrell, Randall. The third book of criticism, circa 1969 (Box 56, Folder 807)
  - Jasen, David A., ed. The uncollected Wodehouse
  - Jeffers, Robinson. The beginning and the end, circa 1963 (Box 56, Folder 808)
  - Johnson, Samuel. Selected poetry and prose, circa 1977 (Box 56, Folder 809-810)
  - Jones, James
    - The pistol, circa 1959 (Box 56, Folder 811)
    - Viet journal, circa 1974 (Box 56, Folder 812)